字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
I see.
是嗎？
So Canute has died?
庫奴特死了？
No, to be precise, he is missing.
不，確切來說是下落不明
Ragnar's troop intended to rescue Prince Canute
拉古納爾的軍隊試圖解救庫奴特王子
and crossed swords with Thorkell's army at Marlborough.
在馬爾波羅與托魯克爾的人馬交戰
Amidst the chaos
王子殿下在混亂中失蹤了
Then are they still surrounded by Thorkell's army?
那他們被托魯克爾的人包圍了嗎？
Yes.
是的
However,
但是交戰的兩天後
His Highness was not found among the enemy army.
敵軍裡沒有見到王子殿下的身影
It may be that he has survived and is awaiting rescue.
可能活了下來，正等待救援
But even if we send help,
但就算我們派援軍
we would have to wait until spring.
也得等到春天才能出動
I cannot fathom the worry you must be feeling, Your Majesty.
陛下的擔憂之情，臣難以想像
If only
要是…
Canute had exceeded his older brother Harald's abilities,
庫奴特擁有超越他哥哥哈羅德的才能
then perhaps he wouldn't have disappeared.
或許就不會失蹤了
Oh, it's snowing.
下雪了
The war will end soon.
戰爭要結束了
Winter,
冬天
do you intend to freeze even the hearts of warriors?
你難道連戰士的心都要凍結嗎？
Oh, winter!
冬天啊！
Commander!
老大！
Do you want to eat roasted or stewed pork?
你想吃烤豬肉還是燉豬肉？
Both!
兩個都要！
Swallow first. I can't understand you.
我聽不懂，吞下去再說
it was painful watching the prince get away.
眼睜睜看著王子逃掉真是太難過了
No, you handed him over.
不，是你把他交出去的
That prince was a coward, but he could have been useful.
那個王子雖然是個懦夫 但或許能派上用場
He could've been elevated to bring about a new dynasty.
例如把他拱上王位，建立一個新王朝
He'd be effective for consolidating the soldiers.
打著王子的名號招兵買馬也很有用
And if you were to help elevate him, you'd gain some influence.
如果由你來輔佐他 說不定能獲得一些影響力
Right?
就是說啊
Hey! You English maiden!
喂，那邊那個英格蘭妹子
Yes?
什麼事？
Bring me a cask of beer!
沒啤酒了，直接把酒桶搬來
Excuse me!
不好意思！
One more cask of beer!
再一桶啤酒！
Not again, damn it!
還要喝啊，可惡！
Are these fiends trying to eat the whole village?
那群混帳！ 他們想把整個村子吃空嗎？
At this rate, they might as well have raided us!
這樣下去跟被掠奪根本沒兩樣！
Stop your whining!
別哭！
If he was to be captured either way, I should have handed him to the English.
早知道王子會被搶走 我還不如把他交給英格蘭
Huh? What's so funny?
有什麼好笑的？
You're troubled, aren't you?
你很煩惱吧？
When the fires of war burn low, you look for another spark.
戰火快平息時 你又開始找另一個火花
Of course I do, bastard.
那是當然的
We're warriors, are we not?
我們是戰士，不是嗎？
We're only warriors if we're on a battlefield.
戰士就應該在戰場上打仗
But you know, I've heard a bad rumor.
但我聽說了一個壞消息
At the next Witenagemot assembly in Wessex,
威塞克斯下一次的賢者會議
the title of Bretwalda will be bestowed on King Sweyn.
會承認斯韋恩王為不列顛霸主
That would be a total surrender!
那就是完全投降了！
Right.
是啊
Denmark will swallow England whole.
丹麥要吞掉英格蘭了
The nobility wish to end the war even if it means relinquishing the throne.
看來英格蘭貴族不惜捨棄王權 也想結束這場戰爭
Why must all my worst fears come true?
為什麼我不祥的預感老是會成真？
What will you do?
你打算怎麼做？
Will you die honorably fighting King Sweyn's army?
要跟斯韋恩王的軍隊打 然後光榮赴死嗎？
Fool!
笨蛋！
I love a good battle, but I hate losing!
我喜歡好好打一場，但我討厭輸啊！
When I fight, I expect to win!
要打就要贏
How dull.
好無聊
If only the world would just keep fighting forever.
真希望全世界都能一直打仗…
I have a message! Is the feudal lord here?
我來傳話！領主大人在嗎？
Is something wrong, Ear?
大耳，有異狀嗎？
Yeah, it's too damn cold.
有，太冷了
The snow is absorbing the sound,
雪會吸收聲音
so even my range of hearing is limited.
就算我的聽力再好 能聽到的範圍也會變小
It's better than sending out scouts.
這還是比派人步哨好
This way no one will know we're here.
這樣才不會被發現我們在這裡
Then do something about them.
那你也管管他們吧
Nobody would mistake them for farmers.
不管怎麼看，他們都不像農夫
The monk and the prince? Keep your ear on them.
修道士他們嗎？你也看著他們
He's saying,
他說：“請原諒我們”
Are they going to beg for forgiveness every time something happens?
難道每次發生什麼事 都要請求寬恕嗎？
What a nuisance.
真麻煩
Oh Lord above…
我們高高在上的天父啊
please summon the souls of these villagers
請將長眠於此的村民靈魂
to be by to your side.
召喚到祢身邊
Please save the souls of those who killed these people.
對於殺害這些人的人 請拯救他們的靈魂
Please, forgive us our sins.
請赦免我們的罪
Is this really the time to be praying for strangers? Fools.
現在是為陌生人祈禱的時候嗎？
Lord…
天父
are my words reaching your ears?
祢有沒有聽見我的聲音？
Our Lord,
天父啊
you
祢以自己的模樣創造我們
But your power was not shared with us.
但祢的能力並沒有分享給我們
Lord…
天父
if the good and the evil are loved with equal measure,
如果祢平等地愛著好人與壞人
for what purpose are the helpless being tested so?
那為什麼要考驗我們這些無助的人？
Lord…
天父
is my voice
祢聽到我的聲音了嗎？
Our Lord,
我們的天父啊
I am doubting
我懷疑…
your love.
祢的愛
Stop!
別說了！
You doubt
你懷疑…
the Lord?
天父嗎？
You still call yourself a believer of Christ?
你還自稱是基督徒？
Fear and tremble!
你膽子也太大了！
We cannot doubt the Lord's love!
我們不能懷疑天父的愛！
There is…
沒有…
There is no father who does not love
沒有哪個父親不愛自己的子女
Your Highness…
殿下
Please wait!
請等一下！
Father.
爸爸
A troop of Danes?
丹麥人的部隊？
Are you serious?
真的假的？
Yes, that's what the messenger said.
對，傳話的人是這麼說的
They're occupying a village further up the River Severn.
看來他們佔領了塞文河上游的小村莊
A local lord has requested help.
當地領主在求援
According to a survivor's story,
倖存的村民說
there were 100 to 200 enemy soldiers.
敵軍大約有一百到兩百人
Soldiers from surrounding areas are already on their way.
附近的士兵已經趕過去了
If you, the great warrior Thorkell, would be willing to help, then please…
如果大名鼎鼎的戰士托魯克爾 願意出面協助就太好了
What do you think?
你覺得呢？
Regardless of what I think,
不管怎麼看
there aren't many Danish troops who'd act on their own
這個季節加上那種位置 幾乎不會有其他丹麥部隊
in this season in that position.
單獨行動
They feigned for the sea, but headed for Gainsborough by land.
他們假裝走水路 其實是走陸路前往蓋恩斯伯勒
So they're trapped in the snow and are resting?
所以他們被積雪困住，正在休息嗎？
That is the most likely scenario.
十之八九是這樣
It's Thorfinn and Canute.
是托爾芬和庫奴特
All right!
好！
Wake everyone up! Prepare to march!
叫醒大家！準備出發！
Yes, sir.
是！
You two.
還有…
-Yeah, you. -Yes?
-喂，你啊 -什麼事？
Prepare food for our journey.
幫我們準備食物
I want 500 servings for five days.
夠五百人吃五天的份量就好
What? 500 servings?
什麼？五百…
So it begins.
很好
Things are getting interesting.
這下有意思了
If this battle goes my way,
要是這場仗打得順利
I may still have some fun.
說不定還有得玩呢
How many, Ear?
大耳，有多少人？
Not sure.
不確定
It could be 50 or 100.
五十或一百人
They're extending their line along the woods in the east.
他們沿著樹林往東佈下包圍線
They sniffed us out quickly.
這麼快就找到我們了
Did we miss someone?
哪裡出錯了嗎？
Who knows?
誰知道？
But this revelation can't be helped.
但被發現了也沒辦法
We're leaving?
我們要走了？
It's impossible to leave tonight.
不可能在今晚出發
I've only finished two sleds.
我只做了兩輛雪橇
I started the third only yesterday.
昨天才開始做第三輛
Really? Well done.
這樣啊，辛苦了
Finish it by nightfall.
那就在天黑前完成
Drop whatever can't be finished by then.
來不及做完的話就放棄
I'm telling you, it's impossible.
不可能
There are only two carpenters.
木匠只有兩個
The English army has found us.
英格蘭軍隊發現我們了
What? They found us?
什麼？被發現了？
Yes. They're pushing their way through the snow now.
對，不惜穿越積雪過來了
They seem to have an intense aversion to Danes.
看來他們很鄙視丹麥人
It can't be.
怎麼會…
This is our only chance to escape.
再不快點就沒機會逃了
If you understand, get moving.
如果聽懂了，就快點做吧
Yes. All right.
好
Bjorn, get the men prepared for a counter-attack.
表倫，叫手下準備迎戰
We'll seize their commanding officer.
抓住敵方的指揮官
I want to know how they discovered us.
我想知道他們是怎麼發現我們的
Understood.
好
Wait a moment, Bjorn.
表倫，等一下
One more thing.
還有一件事
This is an opportunity.
這是個好機會
to do that other thing.
順便把那件事做一做
We've been found?
被發現了？
This is bad.
這不是很糟嗎？
It'll be fine.
不會有事的
The English are weak.
英格蘭士兵很弱
No, that's not what I mean.
不，我不是說這個
I'm talking about Askeladd's luck.
我是說阿謝拉特的運氣
His luck?
運氣？
First, the heavy snowfall and now this.
先是遇到大雪，現在又是這個
This is the first time his plans haven't gone smoothly.
他的計畫進行得這麼不順利 這還是頭一遭
That's a delicious-looking rabbit.
那隻兔子好像很美味
Did you catch it, Thorfinn?
托爾芬，是你抓到的嗎？
What?
什麼？
Are you going to eat that alone? Will you roast it?
你要一個人吃嗎？
What's your point?
你到底想說什麼？
Eating only meat isn't good for you.
只吃肉對身體不好
Simmer it with some vegetables.
加點蔬菜燉煮
Make that rabbit into a stew.
做成湯來喝吧
Shut up.
少囉嗦
I'll eat my food however I want.
我想怎麼吃就怎麼吃
You'll need a stove either way.
不管怎樣你都得借個灶吧
Come on in.
進來吧
Your Highness! We have fava beans, cabbage, and rabbit.
殿下，我們有蠶豆、甘藍和兔子
Rabbit?
兔子？
Yes.
是的
Thorfinn caught it.
托爾芬抓到的
Will you contribute it to the soup?
您覺得加進湯裡如何？
Good job.
辛苦了
Drain the blood and clean the innards.
放血之後把內臟洗乾淨
Not bad for some crude ingredients.
食材不怎麼樣，味道卻不錯
It's the rabbit.
多虧了那隻兔子
I was tired of eating salted meat.
我已經吃膩醃肉了
Thank you.
謝謝你
What's wrong? No need to hold back.
怎麼了？不用客氣
It's your rabbit.
兔子是你抓到的
It's good, isn't it?
很好吃吧？
Next time, bring us a deer!
下次抓一隻鹿回來
I thought royalty didn't cook their own food.
我以為皇室成員只會吃，不會做飯
It's a hobby.
這是我的興趣
I normally don't cook,
我通常不做飯的
and only Ragnar knows about it.
只有拉古納爾知道
Please don't tell anyone.
請不要告訴別人
It's not a bad thing.
這又不是壞事
A long time ago,
很久以前
I once cooked a cod.
我做了鱈魚料理
I thought it turned out well, so I brought it to my father.
我覺得很不錯，就拿去給父王吃
But before tasting it, he flew into a rage.
結果他連吃都沒吃就大發雷霆
He said, "The son of a king does not cook like a lowly slave."
他說：“國王的兒子 不能像低賤奴隸一樣”
After that, I was forbidden to cook.
在那之後，我就被禁止做飯了
There is no need for a prince to have this skill.
王子不需要學習那種技能
That was a time when His Majesty was busy with many things.
國王陛下當時太忙了
When the war is over, we'll cook some fowl and bring it to him.
戰爭結束後 我們來做禽肉料理給他吃
Surely, the king will be overjoyed.
陛下一定會很高興
What kind of fowl?
什麼樣的禽肉？
I've never cooked fowl before.
我沒煮過禽肉
It could be chicken or duck.
雞肉或鴨肉之類的
Remember the duck you ate for Yule?
您記得以前在冬至時吃過的鴨肉嗎？
Yes, that was delicious.
記得，那個很好吃
I asked the cook for his secret recipe.
我後來向廚師問他的祕方是什麼
He said he made good use of the broth.
他說要好好運用高湯
The broth? I see.
高湯？這樣啊
Ragnar!
拉古納爾…
You idiot! I've got a message!
白痴，我是來傳話的！
What is it? What happened?
怎麼了？發生什麼事？
We've been found by the enemy.
我們被敵人發現了
They're already fighting in the eastern forest.
他們已經在東邊的樹林裡打起來了
What?
什麼？
Their numbers seem low, but we must still take precautions.
他們的人數不多，但還是要小心
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
We've only been hiding here for ten days!
我們只在這裡躲了十天！
How were we found?
為什麼會被發現？
How should I know!
我怎麼知道！
What a disaster.
怎麼會這樣…
They killed all those villagers.
殺光村民到底是為了什麼…
In any case,
不管怎樣
if we can hold off the English, be prepared to move.
就算能打敗英格蘭士兵 我們也得準備啟程
This is why I've been saying we should return to Wales!
所以我一開始就說我們該回威爾斯
No, we'll be going to Derby.
不，我們要去德比
We're venturing further into enemy territory?
這種時候還要深入敵地？
Bring Askeladd here!
叫阿謝拉特過來！
Right now!
馬上！
He's commanding the front line.
他正在前線指揮
If you want to talk, you're free to go yourself.
你有話要跟他說，就自己去
I'll take you.
我帶你去
Damn it!
真是的
Subordinates are only as good as their leader!
手下跟首領沒兩樣
You even speak informally!
說話這麼沒禮貌！
He can't even command his own luck! He calls himself a Norse warrior?
連自己的運氣好壞都不知道
Today, by my sword, he'll know the cost of his foolishness.
今天我要用劍教訓他 讓他知道自己有多愚蠢！
Hey!
喂！
The battle cries are over there.
戰鬥聲是從那邊傳來的
You finally noticed?
你終於發現了？
You sure are slow.
你真的很遲鈍
What? What are you bastards suggesting?
什麼？你們這些王八蛋在說…
Black guard.
王八蛋…
Sorry, conehead.
抱歉，尖頭佬
It's Askeladd's orders.
這是阿謝拉特的命令
You want to fight?
你想打嗎？
It doesn't matter to us.
我們是無所謂啦
You're dead either way.
反正你都是死路一條
Call Askeladd here.
叫阿謝拉特過來
There's something he must know.
我有重要的事情要告訴他
If it's your last testament, you can tell me. I'll hear it.
是遺言的話就跟我說吧
Just call him!
叫他過來就對了！
It's regarding the prince!
和王子殿下有關
I must tell him directly.
我必須親口告訴他
Quickly!
快點！
I will hear your last testament.
那我就聽聽你的遺言吧
Shall I dismiss the others?
要叫其他人離開嗎？
The voices stopped.
聲音停止了
The battle is over.
戰鬥結束了
Goodness.
真是的
The stew has gone cold.
湯都涼了
I am grateful to you.
我很感謝你
You've done well protecting that coward of a prince for so long.
竟然成功讓那個膽小的王子活到今天
And your death will surely further his prosperity.
你的死一定會讓他有進一步的成長
I will inherit your duties as of today.
從今天起，我會接替你的工作
After your death in battle,
代替“被英格蘭士兵殺死”的你
I will take over.
輔佐王子殿下
Vow to your gods.
向你的神發誓
Vow that after I'm gone, no matter what happens…
發誓我死後，不管發生什麼事
you will protect Prince Canute.
你都會保護庫奴特殿下
No matter what happens, I will protect Prince Canute
不管發生什麼事 我都會保護庫奴特殿下
so that the death of the warrior Ragnar was not in vain.
不會讓戰士拉古納爾枉死
Satisfied?
滿意了嗎？
How tormenting
真不甘心
that I must entrust the prince to someone like you.
我竟然要把殿下託付給你這種人
You should hurry.
你最好快講
You're losing quite a lot of blood.
你流了很多血
Before Gainsborough…
你在抵達蓋恩斯伯勒之前
you should prepare yourself.
要做好準備
Right now, the courtiers of Jelling
現在耶林的宮中
are fighting over the Danish throne
為了下任丹麥王位的人選
and have split into two factions.
分裂成兩派
Prince Canute is being made the leader of one faction,
其中一派將庫奴特殿下奉為領袖
and the other faction is being led by his elder brother Harald.
另一派擁護殿下的哥哥哈羅德
It is a power struggle among self-interested traitors.
而是奸臣私下的權力鬥爭
And His Majesty fears the Kingdom of Denmark will be divided.
陛下擔心丹麥王國會分裂
He may have already made the decision in his heart…
所以他可能已經決定好…
to kill
要殺了其中一位王子
King Sweyn would kill a prince?
斯韋恩王要殺其中一位王子？
The reason the king has now sent the prince to war
陛下之所以讓殿下親自上戰場
was to have him killed in battle.
就是希望他戰死
Be careful.
你要小心
At this time
庫奴特殿下現在真正的敵人
is none other than his father, King Sweyn.
就是他的父王斯韋恩陛下
That's all you can do now.
現在只能這樣了
In Gainsborough,
在蓋恩斯伯勒
my younger brother
我的弟弟
will make the necessary
應該會…
arrangements.
做好準備…
What a mess.
怎麼這樣啊
You should've told me that earlier!
這種事你應該早點說的
For the last time.
最後
Just one last look.
讓我再看一眼就好
Let me see the prince…
讓我見王子殿下一面
to say goodbye.
跟他道別
No.
不行
Your Highness.
殿下
When the war is over…
等戰爭結束
we'll cook some fowl.
我們一起做禽肉料理吧
Surely,
國王陛下
the king
一定會…
overjoyed.
很高興